Francesco Caglianone
Rome, Italy
+39 345 8339999
francescocaglianone@gmail.com
LinkedIn
GitHub
Personal Website

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER & INVESTMENT MANAGER

As a dynamic Informatics bachelor, I am deeply passionate in the fields of Software Development, FinTech, Finance, Data Science, and Network Science.

My journey has led me to a prestigious role as an Investment Manager for a Capital Management company (London & Carlyle), a position obtained thanks to my exceptional networking and social skills, enhanced by a good foundation in finance and investment.

My networking and social skills come from my insatiable curiosity about the world. I'm not a traveller, I am an explorer. Travelling allows me to immerse myself in new cultures, taste diverse cuisines, understand different religions, and appreciate various ways of living. My various journeys around the globe gifting me with lifelong friendships and unforgettable experiences, that enriched my personal and professional skills by improving my ability to connect, socialize, and integrate with people across different cultures and religions.

I see myself as a determined hard worker. Although I may not always claim to be the smartest, I'm obsessed with achieving excellence and success. I believe that success is not about talent, but about obsession. There are many talented people, but only those obsessed with their goals achieve them.

I am deeply inspired by visionaries and entrepreneurs like Jobs, Bezos, and Musk. Their journeys reflect deeply with my life ambition; to build not just a company but an empire. This belief fuels my commitment in leaving a mark on the industries I am passionate about. My aim is to mix my diverse interests and skills to innovate, lead, and inspire in the evolving world of technology and finance.

I believe Life is like writing a book. At first it is blank, but then we start filling it with our journey. Some pages might be better than others, and some we might wish we could erase. But what really matters is if, in the end, our story is one that others would want to read.

### Education

**2023 – 2024** Copenhagen, Denmark IT-Universitetet, Bachelor in GBI (Global Business Informatics), Exchange Program In my final undergraduate year, I joined an exchange program in Copenhagen to study Global Business Informatics. This augmented my informatics degree by teaching me business strategies in software development and marketing. Highlighting software customization to meet diverse cultural, gender and religious needs and understanding how to connect those software solutions with society.

#### 2021 - 2024

Lugano, Switzerland

#### USI (Universitá della Svizzera Italiana), Bachelor in Informatics

In my bachelor's in informatics I gained a broad experience in software development through a range of group projects, which improved my teamwork and collaborative skills. My studies covered key concepts such as Computer Architecture, Systems Programming, Object-Oriented and Concurrent Programming, Data Management, and Full Stack Web Development, alongside subjects like Calculus, Linear Algebra, Algorithms & Data Structures, and Probability & Statistics. This has given me a strong understanding of both the theoretical and practical aspects of Informatics.

#### 2017 - 2021

Cosenza, Italy

#### Scientific International High School "E. Fermi" Italian-English Option Diploma

I graduated High School with a diploma focused mainly on scientific subjects (Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, and Biology). This program combined the Italian high school syllabus with the British high school curriculum from Cambridge, for which I had to obtain various Cambridge certifications listed below ("Licenses & Certifications"). Courses were taught in both Italian and English, giving me a dual-cultural experience. In addition to this bilingual education, we also studied Spanish as a third language.

#### 2019 - 2020

Lompoc, California (USA)

#### Lompoc High School, Exchange Program

Attended an exchange at Lompoc High School in California, improving my networking and social skills with people from various backgrounds. This experience taught me the value of understanding and blending with different cultures.

# **Professional Experience**

#### Nov 2023 - Ongoing

West Palm Beach, FL (USA)

#### London & Carlyle Capital Management, Investment Manager

As an Investment Manager at London & Carlyle Capital Management, I specialized in debt side investments, proposing to my investors secure and high-profit investment opportunities. My role involves in building relationships and delivering tailored investment strategies that align with our clients' goals.

## Jul 2018 - Sept 2018

Dubai, UAE

## BruBru LLC, Full Stack Web Developer

As a Full Stack Web Developer at BruBru LLC, I created the first version of the company's website, improving user engagement and website performance, and showing my skills in web development.

### Jul 2017 - Sept 2017

Dubai, UAE

### Clariba, Software Engineer

As a software engineer at Clariba, I completed various on-demand tasks, contributing to the development and optimization of various software programs. My role involved in the full software development lifecycle from design, and development to testing, and deployment.

## Licenses & Certifications

### Harvard Professional Certificate in Data Science (2023 - Ongoing)

Given the strong demand for skilled data scientists, I chose to augment my programming abilities by pursuing a professional certificate in data science. In the program I covered a vast array of concepts such as probability, inference, regression, and machine learning helping me to develop a skill set that includes R programming, data wrangling with dplyr, data visualization with ggplot2, file organization with Unix/Linux, version control with git and GitHub, and reproducible document preparation with RStudio.

Data Science: R BasicsData Science: Visualization

• Data Science: Inference and Modelling

• Data Science: Productivity Tools

• Data Science: Wrangling

Data Science: Linear RegressionData Science: Machine Learning

• Data Science: Capstone

#### IGCSE (International General Certificate of Secondary Education by Cambridge University) (2018 - 2020)

During my Scientific International High School Diploma I achieved various International General Certificates of Secondary Education (IGCSE) from Cambridge University, successfully completing both the Italian high school syllabus and the British high school curriculum from Cambridge. I gained a comprehensive understanding of the following subjects:

- IGCSE in Co-ordinated Sciences (Biology, Chemistry and Physics)
- IGCSE in English as a Second Language
- IGCSE in Mathematics
- · IGCSE in Geography.

### Cambridge English Level 1 Certificate in ESOL INTERNATIONAL (2020)

In 2020, I achieved the Cambridge English Level 1 Certificate in ESOL International, demonstrating a strong proficiency in English across reading, writing, listening, and speaking.

### SAT (Standardized College Admission Test) (2019)

Successfully completed the SAT, demonstrating a strong proficiency in Mathematics, Evidence-Based Reading, and Writing.

## **Programming Languages**

Dart: Advanced Java: Proficient C++: Advanced

JavaScript: Intermediate HTML & CSS: Intermediate

Kotlin: NovicePython: Advanced

R: NoviceSQL: Novice

## Tools & Frameworks

- Flutter
- Vue.js
- Node.js
- · Android SDK
- REST APIs
- Git
- GitHub
- Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP)
- Mongo DB
- Firebase
- HPC

# Languages

- Italian Native proficiency
- English Full professional proficiency
- Spanish Limited working proficiency

## Extracurricular Activities

#### 2019 - Ongoing

Cosenza, Italy

#### Dante Global - Societá Dante Alighieri, Member

As a dedicated member of the Societá Dante Alighieri, I am involved in the global promotion of the Italian language and culture. Our mission is to promote appreciation and understanding of Italy's rich cultural heritage, extending far beyond its borders.

#### 2019

Cosenza, Italy

### Universitá Della Calabria, Department of Physics, Pathway

Pathway for soft skills and orientation. I actively engaged in various physics experiments. The experiments were conducted in groups enriching not only my understanding of physics principles but also to improve social skills along with problem-solving and analytical thinking.

#### 2011 - 2019

Lugano, Switzerland

### TASIS (The American School In Switzerland), Student

Each summer from 2011 up to 2019, I participated in the TASIS Summer School program, to improve my English knowledge through speaking, reading, and writing classes. These experience, set me in a culturally diverse environment, deeply improving my networking and social skills to interact with people from various backgrounds. This experiences expanded my network establishing lifelong friendships and professional contacts that I continue to collaborate with. This journey has not only improved significantly my language proficiency but also my interpersonal skills.

### 2018 - 2021

Cosenza, Italy

### Radio Fermi - Enrico Fermi Radio News, Manager and IT Specialist

Throughout my high school years, I co-founded and managed "Radio Fermi" our school's broadcasting and journalism platform. As the manager I supervised the coordination and execution of various tasks, ensuring the smooth operation of our team's projects.

Additionally, I contributed with my IT my expertise by editing videos and photos for our social media channels.

### 2018 - 2021

Cosenza, Italy

## E. Fermi Open Day Ambassador & Exchange Student Program Promoter

Throughout my high school years, I was an ambassador for all the open days and promotional initiatives, engaging with potential future students and their parents. Starting in 2020, I also started promoting the Exchange Student Program, sharing my experience and highlighting its benefits in improving your social skills, enhancing your knowledge, and broadening your horizons.

#### 2018 - 2021

Cosenza, Italy

#### E. Fermi Student IT Specialist

At all students meetings as an IT specialist my responsability was managing the technical equipment, such as microphones, screen projectors, and lighting systems, ensuring high-quality audiovisual experiences for all participants.

## **Highlighted Projects**

### TikTok Network Crawler (Bachelor Research Project)

A Social Network Crawler in Python that, given a user or a list of users, fetches the user's followings from the TikTok API and then recursively fetches the followings of those accounts. This creates a representation of TikTok network to then compare it with other known social networks like Instagram and Meta.

Potential use: This software can also be used to identify trends, and potential market niches within TikTok's ecosystem. Available: TikTok-network-crawler

### Report on the SAS Institute

A case study on the implications of IT, Globalization, and Culture for the SAS Institute. Report made for the IT, Globalization, and Culture course at IT-Universitetet i København (Autumn 2023).

Available: Upon request

## **Hobbies & Interests**

## Travelling

I have a profound passion for traveling, seizing every opportunity to explore new cultures, savor diverse cuisines, and immerse myself in different ways of living.

## • Horse riding

Part of the horse-riding regional team and multiple times winner at national level.

#### Scuba diving

Certified scuba diver (March 2017), dived in Dubai, Maldives, Italy.

#### Skiing

Skiing holds a special place in my heart; it's a passion that my father instilled in me from a young age. Year after year, our family trips to the slopes are among my most cherished memories.

#### Networking Events

I actively participate in networking events, I believe that it is pivotal for personal and professional growth.